Guide to the Yale School of Drama Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale School of Drama records
1923-2008
RU 728
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
140
(253 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, student records, administrative files of the deans, financial and business records, curricula, programs, and slides documenting the activities and operations of the Yale School of Drama and the Yale School of Drama's Student Government.
Yale School of Drama
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 22-A (YRG 22-A), Central records and records of the dean of the Yale School of Drama.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged as follows: I. Correspondence (Select). II. Curricula and Courses. III. Drama Alumni Records. IV. Edward Cole Files. V. Faculty. VI. Financial Records. VII. Plays and Productions. VIII. Student Records; and in subsequent accessions.
Biographical / Historical
In 1924, Yale established the first department of drama in the country with a generous contribution from Edward S. Harkness (B.A. 1897). As part of the School of Fine Arts, the Department of Drama offered a Master of Fine Arts in Drama, first conferred in 1931. The department was headed by George Pierce Baker, formerly of the well-known English "47 Workshop" at Harvard. By vote of the Yale Corporation in 1955, the Department of Drama separated from the School of Fine Arts and became the Yale School of Drama. The new school continued to administer the Master of Fine Arts in Drama as well as a Doctor of Fine Arts in Drama. Continuing a 1927 practice of awarding certificates to promising students who had completed the three year program but lacked the B.A. required for admission, the School of Drama created a new program which would culminate in a Master of Fine Arts. The School of Drama also offers a three year program for a Doctor of Fine Arts in theater criticism.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, student records, administrative files of the deans, financial and business records, curricula, programs, and slides documenting the activities and operations of the Yale School of Drama and the Yale School of Drama's Student Government.
Acting -- Study and teaching; College theater; Drama -- Study and teaching; Theater; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Slides (photographs); Yale School of Drama; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University. Department of Drama
- Correspondence, 1923-1967; Series I
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - CORRESPONDENCE-SELECT
    - ABC Playwriting Program, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - ABC Writing Fellowship, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Alexander, Charlotte, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Allied College Theatres of New England, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - American Architect, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - American Dramatists, Inc. (also: George Middleton), 1926-1930 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - American Educational Theatre Association (AETA)
      - 1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - 1957-1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Art, 1946-1955 (Box 1, Folder 9 - 10)
      - Manuscript Play Project, 1953-1955 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Questionnaire, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Silver Jubilee, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - AETA-TAP Theatre Index-Correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Keynote, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Data Sheets (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Rucker Project, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Suspense File, 1957-1963 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - American Laboratory Theatre, 1925-1928 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - American National Theatre and Academy (ANTA)
      - 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - 1950-1953 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - 1957-1961 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Committee, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - ANTA-Greater New York Chapter, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - American Playwrights Theatre, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - American Shakespeare Festival Theatre, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - American Shakespeare Festival Theatre and Academy, 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - American Shakespeare Festival/Yale Shakespeare Institute, 1953-1962 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Angell, President James R., 1924-1937 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Art Alliance: Philadelphia, 1926-1929 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Associates of Yale Theatre, 1945-1946 (Box 5, Folder 34)
      - Activities, 1941-1948 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Associates of the Yale Theatre Fund: Statements, 1942-1944 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Author's League of America: Financial Statement, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Baker, George Pierce: Opening of University Theater, 1926-1933 (Box 6, Folder 50)
      - Retirement, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Barber, Philip W., 1926-1932 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Benson, John William, 1929-1931 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Brandt and Brandt Dramatf. Dept., Inc., 1960 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - Broadcasting Material; Edward C. Obrist, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Brustein, Robert (Dean), Correspondence for, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 65)
      - Personal, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 66 - 67)
    - Campus Police, 1955-1962 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Campus Police, 1960-1967 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Canfield, F. Curtis; Correspondence, Appointment to Yale, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 72)
      - Memos and Letters, 1954-1956 (Box 7, Folder 73)
      - 1963-1965 (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Carrington, Margaret, 1928-1929 (Box 8, Folder 75)
    - Carroll, Richard C. (Dean of Undergraduate Affairs), 1959-1962 (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - Carolina Playmakers, 1918, 1928 (Box 8, Folder 77)
    - CBS, 1955-1958 (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Chicago: Yale Festival of Arts, 1955-1956 (Box 8, Folder 80)
    - Church and Drama League of America, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - Coffee Room, 1926-1929 (Box 8, Folder 82)
    - Cole, Charles W. (Amherst College President), 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 83)
    - Cole, Edward C., 1927-1928 (Box 8, Folder 84)
      - 1932-1940 (Box 8, Folder 85)
      - Airlines, Special Student Fares, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 86)
      - Misc. Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 87)
    - Collection: Warren C. Crane, 1926-1928 (Box 8, Folder 88)
    - Collections Offered for Sale, 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 89 - 90)
    - Conaway, Gladys K., 1937-1940 (Box 8, Folder 91)
    - Connecticut College, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 92)
    - Connelly, Marc, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - Crawford, Jack (Professor), 1925-1933 (Box 9, Folder 94)
    - Critics, Guest, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 95)
    - Day, George Parmly, 1926-1941 (Box 9, Folder 98)
    - Dean, Alexander, 1925-1937 (Box 9, Folder 99)
      - 1932-1940 (Box 9, Folder 100)
    - Dean, Virginia D., 1944-1953 (Box 9, Folder 101)
    - Dean's Office: Yale College, 1945-1962 (Box 9, Folder 102)
    - de Liagre, Alfred, Committee on Dept. of Drama, 1947-1962 (Box 9, Folder 103)
    - Dodd, Lee Wilson, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 104)
    - Dramatic Association, 1923-1940 (Box 9, Folder 105)
    - Dramatist Guild (Author's League of America), 1946-1950 (Box 9, Folder 106)
    - Drama League of America, 1925-1931 (Box 9, Folder 107)
    - Drama League Play Contest, 1926-1929 (Box 9, Folder 108)
    - Dramatists Play Service, 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 109)
    - Drama Tournament, New Haven., 1928-1930 (Box 9, Folder 110)
    - Eaton, Walter Prichard, 1932-1957 (Box 9, Folder 112)
      - 1946-1966 (Box 10, Folder 113)
    - Elson, Elizabeth, 1933-1937 (Box 10, Folder 114)
    - Esler, Lemist, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 115)
      - 1949-1962 (Box 10, Folder 116)
    - Encyclopedia Article on Theatre (Collier's), 1947-1949 (Box 10, Folder 117)
    - Eugene O'Neill Benefit, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 118)
    - European Tour, Report of, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 120)
    - Farnham, Thomas W., 1925-1940 (Box 10, Folder 121)
    - Festival of Yale Playwrights, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 122)
    - Film Rentals, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 123)
    - Fisher, Samuel R., 1925-1931 (Box 10, Folder 124)
    - Foreign Translations, 1934-1935 (Box 10, Folder 125)
    - Foreign Trips, Theatre Collection, Students PhD., 1935 (Box 10, Folder 126)
    - Fortieth Anniversary of Drama School (1964-1965), 1963-1965 (Box 10, Folder 127)
    - French, Samuel, 1929-1931 (Box 10, Folder 129)
    - The Fulbright Act, 1949-1961 (Box 10, Folder 130)
    - Furniss, E.S. (Provost)
      - 1939-1946 (Box 10, Folder 131)
      - 1946-1956 (Box 10, Folder 132)
    - Rosamond Gilder Award (Latin American Plays), 1958-1960 (Box 10, Folder 133)
    - Graduate School, 1932-1940 (Box 10, Folder 134)
    - Grahn, Mary - Librarian, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 135)
    - Grieshaber Collection, 1928-1933 (Box 10, Folder 136)
      - Wilder, Isabel, 1929-1931 (Box 10, Folder 137)
    - Guggenheim Foundation, 1927-1933 (Box 11, Folder 138)
    - Harkness, Edward S.
      - 1926-1933 (Box 11, Folder 140)
      - 1933-1934 (Box 11, Folder 141)
    - Harkness, Mrs. Edward S., 1947 (Box 11, Folder 142)
    - Harvard Theatre Collection: Shaw, Robert G., Hall, Lillian A., 1925-1928 (Box 11, Folder 143)
    - Heffner, Hubert (Stanford Univ.), 1948-1954 (Box 11, Folder 145)
    - Institute of International Education (I.I.E.), 1961-1963 (Box 11, Folder 148)
    - International Theatre Institute, UNESCO (Rosamond Gilder), 1949-1951 (Box 11, Folder 149)
    - Izenour, George, 1940-1943 (Box 11, Folder 150)
    - Jessner, Dr. Friedrich, 1940-1943 (Box 11, Folder 151)
    - Jitney Players, Suggestions for productions on the road, 1924 (Box 11, Folder 152)
    - Keogh, Andrew, Library, 1925-1941 (Box 11, Folder 154)
    - Lawrence University, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 157)
    - Library, general, 1930-1946 (Box 12, Folder 159)
    - Library, Sterling, 1933-1945 (Box 12, Folder 160)
      - Committee, 1939-1941 (Box 12, Folder 161)
    - Libraries: Italy, Letter and lists by critics, 1935-1937 (Box 12, Folder 162)
    - Lohman, Carl A., 1926-1947 (Box 12, Folder 164)
    - Mabie, E.C., 1930-1954 (Box 12, Folder 165)
    - MacGowan, Kenneth, 1926-1932 (Box 12, Folder 166)
    - Mansion House (First House for Drama Dept.), 1925-1926 (Box 12, Folder 167)
    - Manuscripts, unsolicited, 1966-1967 (Box 12, Folder 168)
    - Marionettes, 1926-1935 (Box 13, Folder 169)
    - Marionettes, Italian - Purchased and held for Harry L. Burnett, 1928-1929 (Box 13, Folder 170)
    - Marionettes (N.Y. Times Advertisement), 1930 (Box 13, Folder 171)
    - McClintic, Guthrie, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 175)
    - McMullan, Frank A., 1930-1938 (Box 13, Folder 176)
      - 1936-1946 (Box 13, Folder 177)
    - Meeks, Everett V. (Dean)
      - 1925-1933 (Box 13, Folder 178)
      - 1933-1942 (Box 13, Folder 179)
      - 1943-1946 (Box 13, Folder 180)
    - Mei, Lan-Fang, Proposed Visit to New Haven, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 181)
    - Memoranda, lists, addresses, 1925-1947 (Box 14, Folder 182)
    - Metropolitan Museum, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 183)
    - Motion Pictures, 1925-1928 (Box 15, Folder 185)
      - 1926-1935 (Box 15, Folder 186)
    - National Association of Teachers of Speech, 1931-1942 (Box 15, Folder 187)
    - National Broadcasting Company (NBC), 1955-1956 (Box 15, Folder 188)
    - National Committee on Regional Conferences, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 189)
    - National Conference on Drama, Comments and Appreciations, 1927 (Box 15, Folder 190)
    - National Conference: Committee on Royalties, 1927-1930 (Box 15, Folder 191)
    - National Conference on Drama, Pittsburgh, Conference Committee Meetings, 1926 (Box 15, Folder 192)
      - Program and Committee Dinner, 1927 (Box 15, Folder 193 - 194)
      - Yale Administration, 1927 (Box 16, Folder 195)
    - National Theatre Conference
      - 1932 (Box 16, Folder 196)
      - 1934-1942 (Box 16, Folder 197 - 198)
      - 1937-1941 (Box 16, Folder 199)
      - 1942-1943 (Box 16, Folder 200)
      - 1946-1955 (Box 16, Folder 201)
    - National Theatre Conference at New Haven, 1934-1935 (Box 17, Folder 202)
    - National University Theatre Festival: Washington, 1964-1965 (Box 17, Folder 203)
    - National Youth Administration, 1935-1936 (Box 17, Folder 204)
    - New Dramatists Committee, Inc., 1955-1961 (Box 17, Folder 205)
    - New Haven Chamber of Commerce, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 206)
    - Newton, Lieutenant W.I., New London Submarine Base, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 207)
    - Oenslager, Donald M. (Faculty), 1926-1947 (Box 17, Folder 208)
      - 1934-1936 (Box 17, Folder 209)
    - Office of the Provost, 1964-1966 (Box 17, Folder 210)
    - Office of University Development, 1948-1949 (Box 17, Folder 211)
    - Old English Galleries: Antique Clock in Green Room, 1925-1929 (Box 17, Folder 212)
    - Opera Project: Bartholomew, Marshall, 1949-1955 (Box 17, Folder 214)
    - Osborne, Hubert, 1925-1933 (Box 17, Folder 215)
    - Other Departments of Drama, 1936-1963 (Box 17, Folder 216)
    - Pageants and Pageant Materials, 1907-1933 (Box 17, Folder 217)
    - Photography (Correspondence with A. Burton Street), 1961 (Box 18, Folder 219)
    - Pillot, Eugene, 1930 (Box 18, Folder 220)
    - Preminger, Otto Ludwig, 1939 (Box 18, Folder 221)
    - Press: Publicity, 1955-1959 (Box 18, Folder 222)
    - Press: Yale University, Mr. Baker's Criticisms, 1926-1933 (Box 18, Folder 223)
    - Publicity
      - 1930-1933 (Box 18, Folder 224)
      - 1931-1935 (Box 18, Folder 225)
      - 1931-1942 (Box 18, Folder 226 - 227)
      - 1942 (Box 18, Folder 228)
      - 1943-1947 (Box 19, Folder 229)
      - 1944-1945 (Box 19, Folder 230)
    - Publicity Contracts, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 231)
    - Questionnaires from Other Drama Depts., 1951-1957 (Box 19, Folder 232)
    - Radio: Advisory Faculty, American School of the Air, 1929-1933 (Box 19, Folder 233)
    - Radio Corporation of America (RCA), 1955-1957 (Box 19, Folder 234)
    - Radio: Use of Workshop Plays, 1929-1947 (Box 19, Folder 235)
    - Rapp, Dr. Franz, 1935-1942 (Box 19, Folder 236)
    - Recommendations, 1966-1968 (Box 19, Folder 237)
    - Reveaux, Edward C.: flay Production, 1945-1947 (Box 19, Folder 238)
    - Richards. Lloyd (Dean Designate), 1978-1979 (Box 19, Folder 239)
    - Rockefeller Case Account, 1935-1942 (Box 19, Folder 240)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1933-1942 (Box 20, Folder 241 - 242)
      - Izenour, 1946-1947 (Box 20, Folder 243)
    - Rockefeller Foundation: Motion Pictures, 1936-1940 (Box 20, Folder 244)
    - Rockefeller Grant: Distribution of Funds, Ph.D work, 1934-1942 (Box 20, Folder 245 - 246)
      - 1934-1942 (Box 21, Folder 247)
    - Sawyer, Charles H. (Dean), 1949-1956 (Box 21, Folder 250)
    - School of Fine Arts: General, 1925-1928 (Box 21, Folder 251)
    - Seymour, Charles (President), 1937 (Box 21, Folder 252)
    - Shakespeare Festival, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 253)
    - Smith, Boyd M., 1925-1934 (Box 21, Folder 255)
      - 1925-1943 (Box 21, Folder 256)
      - 1954-1957 (Box 21, Folder 257)
      - Agents, 1947-1954 (Box 21, Folder 258)
      - Trip, 1949-1950 (Box 21, Folder 259)
    - Southern, Edward H., 1925-1931 (Box 21, Folder 260)
    - Southern Playwriting Contest (Dan Leed), 1927-1928 (Box 21, Folder 261)
    - Speech Association of America, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 262)
    - State Department, 1948-1951 (Box 21, Folder 263)
    - Theatre Arts Magazine, 1951-1959 (Box 21, Folder 264)
    - Theatre Arts Monthly: Advertising, etc., 1925-1947 (Box 21, Folder 265)
    - Theatre Centre, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 266)
    - Theatre Collection, 1926-1943 (Box 22, Folder 267)
      - General Information, undated (Box 22, Folder 268)
    - Theatre Schools, 1941-1947 (Box 22, Folder 269)
    - Theatrework, Warren Tate, 1966-1967 (Box 22, Folder 270)
    - United Service Organization, 1928-1943 (Box 22, Folder 271)
    - U.S. Office of Education, 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 272)
    - University Council Committee for Drama, 1948-1965 (Box 22, Folder 273)
    - Visitors, 1947-1957 (Box 22, Folder 274)
    - Warren, Robert Penn, 1952-1962 (Box 22, Folder 275)
    - Welch, Constance (Faculty), 1929-1941 (Box 22, Folder 278)
    - Wells, Halstead, 1934 (Box 22, Folder 279)
    - White, Emily V., 1935-1936 (Box 22, Folder 280)
    - Wilmurt, Arthur, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 281)
    - Yale Corporation, 1956-1967 (Box 22, Folder 283)
  - CORRESPONDENCE-GENERAL
    - A, 1929-1930 (Box 23, Folder 285)
    - A, 1935-1942 (Box 23, Folder 286)
    - A, 1954-1957 (Box 23, Folder 287)
    - A, 1957-1962 (Box 23, Folder 288)
    - A, 1963-1967 (Box 23, Folder 289)
    - A-F, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 290)
    - B, 1935-1942 (Box 23, Folder 291)
    - B, 1946-1956 (Box 23, Folder 292)
    - B, 1957-1958 (Box 23, Folder 293)
    - B, 1959-1962 (Box 24, Folder 294)
    - B, 1963-1966 (Box 24, Folder 295)
    - C, 1935-1942 (Box 24, Folder 296)
    - C, 1947-1957 (Box 24, Folder 297)
    - C, 1957-1962 (Box 24, Folder 298)
    - C, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 299)
    - D, 1935-1942 (Box 24, Folder 300)
    - D, 1946-1962 (Box 25, Folder 301)
    - D, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 302)
    - E, 1927-1933 (Box 25, Folder 303)
    - E, 1949-1962 (Box 25, Folder 304)
    - E, 1963-1967 (Box 25, Folder 305)
    - E-F, 1935-1942 (Box 25, Folder 306)
    - F, 1930-1962 (Box 25, Folder 307)
    - G, 1932-1941 (Box 25, Folder 308)
    - G, 1935-1942 (Box 25, Folder 309)
    - G-L, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 310)
    - H, 1926-1933 (Box 25, Folder 311)
    - H, 1946-1952 (Box 25, Folder 312)
    - H-I, 1935-1942 (Box 26, Folder 313)
    - I, 1930 (Box 26, Folder 314)
    - J-K-L, 1935-1942 (Box 26, Folder 315)
    - K, 1930-1932 (Box 26, Folder 316)
    - L, 1926-1950 (Box 26, Folder 317)
    - M, 1930-1931 (Box 26, Folder 318)
    - M, 1935-1942 (Box 26, Folder 319)
    - M-Z, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 320)
    - N-Z, 1935-1942 (Box 26, Folder 321)
    - Q, 1925-1930 (Box 26, Folder 322)
    - Ra-Rn, 1929-1932 (Box 26, Folder 323)
    - Ro-Rz, 1934 (Box 26, Folder 324)
    - S, 1947-1954 (Box 26, Folder 325)
    - Sa-Sd, 1930-1933 (Box 26, Folder 326)
    - Se-Sm, 1926-1934 (Box 26, Folder 327)
    - Sn-Sth, 1932 (Box 27, Folder 328)
    - Sti-Sz, 1931-1934 (Box 27, Folder 329)
    - T, 1927-1932 (Box 27, Folder 330)
    - Miscellaneous, 1925-1947 (Box 27, Folder 331)
      - 1927-1928 (Box 27, Folder 332)
      - 1928-1929 (Box 27, Folder 333)
      - 1929-1930 (Box 27, Folder 334)
      - 1930-1931 (Box 27, Folder 335)
      - 1931-1932 (Box 27, Folder 336)
      - 1932-1933 (Box 27, Folder 337)
      - 1933-1934 (Box 27, Folder 338)
      - 1934-1935 (Box 28, Folder 339)
      - 1935-1936 (Box 28, Folder 340)
      - 1936-1937 (Box 28, Folder 341)
      - 1937-1938 (Box 28, Folder 342)
      - 1938-1939 (Box 28, Folder 343)
      - 1940-1941 (Box 28, Folder 344)
      - 1941-1942 (Box 28, Folder 345)
      - 1942-1944 (Box 28, Folder 346)
      - 1944-1945 (Box 28, Folder 347)
      - 1945-1946 (Box 29, Folder 348)
      - 1946-1947 (Box 29, Folder 349)
      - 1946-1954 (Box 29, Folder 350)
      - 1948-1949 (Box 29, Folder 351)
      - 1949-1950 (Box 29, Folder 352)
      - 1950-195 1 (Box 29, Folder 353)
      - 1954-1955 (Box 29, Folder 354)
      - 1950-1963 (Box 29, Folder 355)
      - 1951-1953 (Box 29, Folder 356)
      - 1953-1959 (Box 30, Folder 357)
      - 1969-1979 (Box 30, Folder 358)
- Curricula and courses, Series II
  - Book List, 1948-1950 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Catalogue, 1943 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Catalogue Materials, 1943-1944 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Catalogue, 1955-1956 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Catalogue, 1956-1957 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Course Lists, 1949-1950 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Courses: Class Lists, 1945-1946 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Midyear Student Schedules, 1946-1947 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Registration, 1946-1947 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Student Notices (Undergraduate), 1943-1944 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Undergraduate, 1940-1947 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Curriculum, 1950-1966 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Theatre Engineering, M.F.A., 1961 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Theatre History and Criticism, Ph.D., 1933-1939 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Degrees: General Information, 1955-1960 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Department, Development of, 1930 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - History of, 1946 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Dept. Procedure: Stage Manager Manual - E. Cole, Drama by A. Dean, 1945 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Doctor of Fine Arts Degree, 1956-1957 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Dramatic Literature and Directing, 1961 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Educational Policy Committee, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Essays and Production Books, 1962-1967 (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Examination Papers (Questions), 1932-1946 (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - Examinations and Comprehensive Questions, 1941-1942 (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - Extension Courses, 1943 (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - Forms: Obsolete (Box 32, Folder 27)
  - Grading: Rules and Information, 1943-1955 (Box 32, Folder 28)
  - Graduate Work towards Ph.D., 1934-1935 (Box 32, Folder 29)
    - Plan and Organization, 1933-1934 (Box 32, Folder 30)
  - History of the Drama School, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 31)
  - Lecturers, Possible, 1928-1944 (Box 32, Folder 32)
    - Visiting, 1952-1953 (Box 33, Folder 33)
    - 1954-1957 (Box 33, Folder 34)
  - Lectures
    - 1925-1926 (Box 33, Folder 35)
    - 1926-1927 (Box 33, Folder 36)
    - 1927-1928 (Box 33, Folder 37)
    - 1928-1929 (Box 33, Folder 38)
    - 1929-1933 (Box 33, Folder 39)
    - 1940-1943 (Box 33, Folder 40)
    - 1945-1946 (Box 33, Folder 41)
    - 1946-1951 (Box 34, Folder 42)
  - Mailing List, Program-Catalogue, 1948-1958 (Box 34, Folder 43)
  - M.F.A. Degree in Production, Suggested Regulations, 1936-1942 (Box 34, Folder 44)
  - Newspaper Accounts of Lectures, 1966-1967 (Box 34, Folder 45)
  - Origin and Development Academically, 1923-1931 (Box 34, Folder 46)
  - Ph.D. Degree, 1947 (Box 34, Folder 47)
  - Play Selection Committee, 1947 (Box 34, Folder 48)
  - Policy File, 1945-1965 (Box 34, Folder 49)
  - Reading Lists, 1965-1966 (Box 34, Folder 50)
  - Report of the Director's Seminar, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 51)
  - Schedule, 1965-1966 (Box 34, Folder 52)
  - Speaking Engagements, 1966-1968 (Box 34, Folder 53 - 54)
  - Speech Course: Army and Navy, 1942-1943 (Box 35, Folder 55)
  - Summer Session: General Information, 1942 (Box 35, Folder 56)
  - Television Material, 1953-1965 (Box 35, Folder 57)
  - Trowbridge Memorial Lectures, 1935-1936 (Box 35, Folder 58)
  - War Effort, School Activities Concerned with, 1942-1945 (Box 35, Folder 59)
  - Miscellaneous Biographies, 1965-1966 (Box 35, Folder 60)
- Drama alumni records, 1932-1968; Series III
  - Alumni: Activities, 1943-1958 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Addresses and Information, 1944-1945 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Board, 1955-1959 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Board Reports, 1953 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence-Placement, Requests for Transcripts, 1964-1969 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Drama Fund, 1956-1963 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Executive Committee, 1961-1963 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Newsletter, 1947-1954 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Notes, 1939-1946 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Notes and Activities, 1940-1955 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - 1946 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - 1956-1961 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Notes-Summer Theatre Information, 1940 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Publicity, 1934-1935 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - 1943 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - 1945-1946 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Replies to E.C. Cole's Questionnaire, 1965-1966 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Benefactor's Party, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - C-note: 2 Letters from Alumni Presenting Gifts, 1961 (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Drama Alumni Association: Activities, 1932-1967 (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - Alumni Questionnaire, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - Beginnings of, 1955 (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1948-1951 (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - Drama Alumni Association: Executive Committee, 1948-1952 (Box 37, Folder 24)